Pop.
Six.
Squish.
Uh-uh.
Cicero.
Lipschitz.
He had it coming
He only had himself to blame
If you'd been there
If you'd seen it
I betcha you would
have done the same
Pop.
Six.
Squish.
Uh-uh.
Cicero.
Lipschitz!
Pop.
Six.
Squish.
Uh-uh.
Cicero.
Lipschitz!
You know how people have these
little habits that get you down?
Like Bernie.
Bernie liked to chew gum.
No, not chew. Pop.
So I came home this one day,
and I am really irritated...
and I'm looking for a little bit
of sympathy, and there's Bernie...
lying on the couch, drinking
a beer and chewing.
No, not chewing. Poping.
So, I said to him, I said,
"You pop that gum one more time..."
And he did. So I took
the shotgun off the wall...
and I fired two warning
shots into his head.
He had it coming
He only had himself to blame
If you'd been there
If you'd heard it
I betcha you would
have done the same
I met Ezekiel Young from Salt
Lake City about two years ago...
and he told me he was single,
and we hit it off right away.
So we started living together.
He'd go to work, he'd come home.
I'd fix him a drink,
we'd have dinner.
And then I found out.
"Single" he told me?
Single my ass.
Not only was he married,
no, he had six wives.
One of those Mormons,
you know.
So that night when he
came home from work...
I fixed him his
drink as usual.
You know, some guys just
can't hold their arsenic.
He had it coming
He took a flower in its prime
And then he used it
And he abused it
It was a murder
but not a crime
Now, I'm standing in the kitchen
carving up a chicken for dinner...
minding my own business. In storms
my husband Wilbur, in a jealous rage.
You been screwing the milkman,
he says. He was crazy.
And he kept on screaming.
You been screwing the milkman!
And then he ran into my knife.
He ran into my knife 1O times.
If you'd been there
If you'd seen it
I betcha you would
have done the same
Yeah, but did you do it?
Uh-uh, not guilty!
He had it coming
My sister Veronica and
I had this double act...
and my husband, Charlie,
traveled around with us.
For the last number in our act,
we did this twenty acrobatic tricks in a row.
One, two, three, four, five.
Splits, spread eagles, back flips,
flip flops, one right after the other.
So this one night before the show
we're down at the hotel Cicero...
the three of us boozing
and havin' a few laughs...
and we ran out of ice,
so I go out to get some.
I come back, open the door...
and there's Veronica and
Charlie doing number seventeen...
the spread eagle.
Well, I was in such a state of shock.
I completely blacked out.
I can't remember a thing.
It wasn't until later, when I was
washing the blood off my hands...
I even knew they were dead.
They had it coming
They had it coming all along
I didn't do it
She didn't do it
But if I'd done it
But if she'd done it
How could you tell
me that I was wrong?
They had it coming
They had it coming all along
I didn't do it
But if I'd done it
How could you tell me
that I was wrong?
I loved Alvin Lipschitz more
than I can possibly say.
He was a real artistic guy,
sensitive, a painter.
But he was always
trying to find himself.
He'd go out every night looking
for himself and, on the way...
he found Ruth, Gladys,
Rosemary...
and Irving.
I guess you could say we broke up
because of artistic differences.
He saw himself as alive,
and I saw him dead.
The dirty bum, bum
bum, bum, bum
They had it comin'
They had it coming all along
'Cause if they used us
and they abused us
How could you tell us
that we were wrong?
He had it coming
He only had himself to blame
If you had been there
If you had seen it
I betcha you would
have done the same
You pop that gum one more time...
Ten times.
Number seventeen, the spread eagle.
Artistic differences.
Pop.
Six.
Squish.
Uh-uh.
Cicero.
Lipschitz.
Who belongs to them?
What is it to you?
Nothing, I heard
they were Velma's.
Yeah, the Hunyak does all
her laundry for a buck a week.
Fresh towels for the can.
Make it quick.
Hear me out on this.
Now Billy Flynn's set your
trial date for March fifth.
March seventh you'll be acquitted. March
eighth, you know what Mama's gonna do?
Gonna put you back on vaudeville.
So now you're an agent too?
Well, dearie, until Ma Bell installs
a private line in your cell...
...all calls are gonna go through me.
What dough are we talking about?
You know, it 's a crazy world.
I mean, Babe Ruth is wearing rouge and
playing the Palace for five thousand  a week.
Yeah. And what about
someone with real talent?
Well, I been talking to the
boys over William Morris.
And due to your recent activities,
they think they can get you twenty five hundred.
twenty five hundred? Jeez, the most me and
Veronica ever made was three fifty.
Well, that 's what happens when
you have the right representation.
You know what, Mama, I always
wanted to play Big Jim Colisimo's.
Do you think you could get me that?
Big Jim's?
Jeez, I don't know. It 's gonna
take another phone call.
How much is that gonna cost?
Come on, Vel.
I feel about you. You're like family
to me. You're like one of my own.
I'll do it for fifty bucks.
Fifty bucks for a phone call?
You must have got a lot of
wrong numbers, Mama.
Miss Kelly, got your personals.
Freshly pressed by yours truly.
No, no. It 's my pleasure.
Hey, listen.
Can I ask you something?
You know that Harrison guy? He said
that what I done is a hanging case...
and that he's prepared to ask
for the maximum penalty.
Yeah? So?
So, I'm scared.
I sure would appreciate some
advice, I mean, especially from...
someone I admire as much as you.
I always wanted to be on the stage.
Really? What 's your talent?
Washing and drying?
No, no, no.
I danced in a chorus.
That was before I met my husband.
Look, honey, you want some advice?
Here it is, direct from me to you. Keep
your paws off my underwear, okay?
Yeah, okay.
Thanks...
...for nothing.
She's something, ain't she?
I tell you, no matter how big she
gets, she's still as common as ever.
I'd like to help you, dearie.
Take a load off.
So, what do you figure
on using for grounds?
Grounds?
What are you gonna tell the jury?
I figure I'd tell them the truth.
The truth?
One-way ticket to the death house.
Holy mother of God.
Relax. I mean, in this town,
murder is a form of entertainment.
Besides, in forty seven years Cook County
ain't never hung a woman yet.
So the odds are forty seven to one
that they won't hang you.
Jesus Mary Joseph.
You're talkin' to the wrong people.
What you need is Billy Flynn.
Who?
Billy Flynn.
He's only the best criminal
lawyer in all of Illinois.
Tell me what he don't know
about juries and women.
How do you get this Billy Flynn?
Well, not by praying, deary.
First, you give me a hundred dollars.
Then I'll make a phone call.
A hundred dollars? Well, you just...
I mean, it seems pretty
stiff for a phone call.
But it 's worth every cent.
I mean, he's never lost a case
for a female client yet.
And with a sweet little
puss like yours, well...
let 's just say justice ain't
so blind in Chicago.
He's never lost a case?
Never.
Every girl in this place would kill to
have Billy Flynn representing them.
We want Billy
B-l-DOUBLE L-Y
We're all his
He's our kind of a guy
And what luck
'Cause here he is
Ladies and gentlemen, presenting
the silver tongue, the prince.
The one, the only.
Billy Flynn!
I don't care about
expensive things
Cashmere coats, diamond rings
don't mean a thing
All I care about is love
That's what he's here for
I don't care for wearing
silk cravats
Ruby studs, satin spats
Don't mean a thing
All I care about is love
All he cares about is love
Give me two
eyes of blue
...softly saying
I need you
Let me see her
standin' there
and honest, mister,
I'm a millionaire
I don't care for
any fine attire
Vanderbilt might admire
No, no, not me
All I care about is love
All he cares about is love
Good morning, ladies.
Not guilty!
You tell him, sweetheart.
That's what he's here for
Excuse me. Do you remember
anything at all about that night?
I passed out completely, Miss
Sunshine. I can't remember a thing.
Only that I didn't do it.
Any idea who did, dear?
No. But my client offers a reward to
anyone with information about it.
How much is the reward, Miss Kelly?
I don't know, how much?
We'll work it out after the trial.
Now, if there are no more questions...
Miss Kelly and I have
a lot of work to do.
What's all this
about a reward?
Dumb reporters. They'll write it up
wrong, you deny the whole thing later.
Thank you!
One more question...
All he cares about is love
Mr. Flynn, I'm Roxie Hart.
Who?
Mama talked to you about me.
Yeah, right, right. The cute one.
I was hoping you might represent me.
You have five thousand dollars?
That 's a lot of money.
Mama didn't say anything
about five thousand dollars.
Look, Mr. Flynn... I'm not very
good at this sort of thing, but...
maybe we could make some sort
of arrangement between us.
And I can be an awfully
good sport.
Good, you got that out of
your system. Now listen...
you mean just one thing to me.
You call me when you got five thousand dollars.
All he cares about is love
Show me long raven hair
flowin' down, about to there
When I see her runnin' free
keep your money
that's enough for me
I don't care for
driving Packard cars
or smoking long buck cigars
No, no, not me
All I care about is
doin' the guy in
who's picking on you
Twisting the wrist
that's turning the screw
All I care about
is love
He'll see you now.
Well, hello, Andy.
Amos, my name is Amos.
That 's right. Take a seat.
You know, you're
a remarkable man.
Your wife two-times you, plugs the
guy and then tries to pin it on you.
Most men would let a dame like that
swing. But no, you're sticking by her.
Makes you a hero in my eyes.
That's right. I'm a hero.
Did you bring the money?
I didn't do as well
as I hoped, but...
I will, Mr. Flynn. I will.
This is only a thousand.
Plus there's tree hundred I borrowed...
from the guys down at the
garage, and there's seven hundred...
...from the building and loan fund.
Two thousand?
And that 's all I got so far.
But I'll give you twenty dollars off
my salary every week.
I'll give you notes with interest.
Double, triple, until it 's paid.
You came to me yesterday, I didn't
ask you if she's guilty or innocent.
I didn't ask you if she was
drunk or a dope fiend, no!
All I said was, "Do you have
five thousand dollars?" You said yes!
But you don't have five thousand dollars!
So I figure you're a dirty liar and I
don't waste my time with dirty liars!
Look...
I'm real sorry, Mr. Flynn.
On the other hand, your devotion
to your wife is really very touching.
I'll take your wife's case.
And I'll keep it.
Because I play square.
Now look, I don't like
to blow my own horn...
but believe me. If Jesus Christ
had lived in Chicago today...
and if he had five thousand dollars
and had come to me...
things would have
turned out differently.
All right, this is what we're gonna
do. By the end of the week...
I'm gonna have Roxie's name
on every newspaper in town.
Sweetest little jazz killer ever to hit
Chicago. That's the angle I'm after.
You make an announcement,
we're gonna have an auction!
Tell them we gotta raise
some money for her defense.
They'll buy everything she's
ever touched. Everything.
Your shoes, your dresses,
your perfumes, your underwear.
And Victrola records. Like the one I
was playing when I shot the bastard.
I didn't hear that.
Not that I didn't have grounds.
Hey, what are they?
That 's for when we go to trial.
Nobody is gonna care a lick what your
defense is unless they care about you.
So the first thing we gotta do is work
up some sympathy from the press.
And they are not all pushovers
like Mary Sunshine.
But there's one thing
they can never resist.
And that is
a reformed sinner.
Right. So tell me, what was
your favorite subject in school?
I was a real dummy.
Come on. There must be something.
I got high marks in
Courtesy and Hygiene.
Perfect, you wanted
to be a nun.
A nun?
Where were you born?
On a chicken farm
outside of Lubbock.
Beautiful Southern home, filled
with every luxury and refinement.
Where are your parents now?
Probably in their rocking chairs.
They're dead.
Family fortune was swept away.
You're educated at Sacred Heart.
Then you fell into a runaway marriage.
Left you miserable, alone, unhappy.
Of course, you got all swept up
in the mad whirl of the city.
Jazz, cabarets, liquor. You were
drawn like a moth to the flame.
A moth?
And now the mad whirl had ceased...
and you're a butterfly.
Crushed on a wheel!
Which is it?
Is it the moth or the butterfly?
You have sinned and you're sorry!
God, that 's beautiful!
Cut out God. Stay where
you're better acquainted.
Kid, when I'm through with you,
not only will you be acquitted...
every man on that jury will wanna
take you home to meet his mother.
I was born on a beautiful
Southern convent.
What?
Holy shit! I'll never
gonna get this straight!
Pipe down the swearing.
Look, from here on in...
you say nothing rougher than
Oh, dear. Now try again.
I was born on...
Come on, come on.
So I came up with some more
things to do on the witness stand.
I thought I'd get all teary-eyed
and ask for your handkerchief.
Then I thought I'd take
a peek at the jury like this...
and flash them a bit of thigh, huh?
What do you think?
Sounds great.
Hey, don't you wanna hear the rest?
Tomorrow, kiddo.
You're at the top of my list.
Well, well, well.
Sorry to be late, Mr. Flynn.
Hope you aren't too bored.
I like it.
Hey, Pollyanna, I heard your
press conference is tomorrow.
Yeah, what is it to you?
Well, you wanted my advice, right?
Here it is, don't forget Billy Flinn's
number-one client is Billy Flynn.
Meaning what?
Meaning, don't let him
hog the spotlight.
You're the one
they paid to see.
Now remember, we can only
sell them one idea at a time.
I can still see him coming at me
with that awful look in his eyes.
And?
And we... both reached for the gun.
That 's right, you both reached
for the gun. Ready?
Yeah.
Thank you, gentlemen,
gentlemen, Miss Sunshine.
My client 's just entered
the plea of not guilty.
We look forward to a trial at the
earliest possible date. Any questions?
Miss Sunshine.
As you know, my paper is dry.
Do you have any advice for girls,
to avoid the life of jazz...
...and drink?
Absolutely, yes. Mrs. Hart feels that...
it was the tragic combination of liquor
and jazz which lead to...
...her downfall. Next question, please.
Ladies and gentlemen...
I'd just like to say how flattered I
am that you all came to see me.
Yeah, Mrs. Hart is very...
You see, I was a moth...
crushed on the wheel.
You know, a butterfly drawn to the...
I bet you wanna know
why I shot the bastard.
Shut up, dummy.
Mr. Billy Flynn in
The Press Conference Rag.
Notice how his mouth
never moves... almost.
Where'd you come from?
Mississippi
And your parents?
Very wealthy
Where are they now?
Six feet under
But she was granted
one more start.
The convent of
The Sacred Heart
When you get here?
Nineteen twenty
How old were you?
Don't remember
Then what happened?
I met Amos, and he
stole my heart away
Convinced me to elope one day
You poor dear, I can't believe
what you've been through.
A convent girl, a runaway marriage.
Now tell us, Roxie.
Who's Fred Casely?
My ex-boyfriend
Why'd you shoot him?
I was leaving
Was he angry?
Like a madman
Still I said, Fred, move along
She knew that she was doin' wrong
Then describe it
He came toward me
With a pistol?
From my bureau
Did you fight him?
Like a tiger
He had strength
and she had none
And yet we both
reached for the gun
Yes, yes, yes, we both
Yes, we both
Yes, we both reached for the gun
The gun, the gun, the gun
For the gun
Yes, yes, yes, they both
Yes, they both
Yes, they both reached for the gun
The gun, the gun, the gun
For the gun
Understandable
Yes, it's perfectly
understandable
Comprehensible
Not a bit reprehensible
It's so defensible
How're you feeling?
Very frightened
Are you sorry?
Are you kidding?
What's your statement?
All I'd say is
Though my choo-choo jumped the track
I'd give my life to bring him back
And?
Stay away from
What?
Jazz and liquor
And?
And the men who
What?
Play for fun
And what?
That's the thought that
...came upon me
When?
When we both
reached for the gun
Understandable
Yes, it's perfectly
understandable
Comprehensible
Not a bit reprehensible
It's so defensible
Yes, yes, yes, they both
Yes, they both
Yes, they both reached for
Let me hear it!
The gun, the gun, the gun, the gun
Yes, they both reached for the gun
For the gun
A little louder!
Yes, yes, yes, they both
Yes, they both
For the gun, the gun, the gun
Yes, they both reached for the gun
Now you got it!
Yes, yes, yes, they both
Yes, they both
Yes, they both reached for the gun
The gun, the gun, the gun
For the gun
Yes, yes, yes, they both
Yes, they both
Yes, they both reached for the gun
The gun, the gun, the gun
Both reached for the
gun
Move over Al Capone, the Windy City
has taken a new criminal to its heart.
The name on everybody's
lips is Roxie Hart.
The sweetest little lady ever
accused of murder in Chicago.
Women wanna look like her.
Fellows wanna go out with her.
Some little girls even wanna take
her home. Don't get any ideas, lady.
On the other side of town, the D.A.
Promises the little sharpshooter...
will swing before
the year is out.
Who knows? If he lives up
to his word assistant D.A. Harrison...
might become
governor Harrison someday.
At the scene of the crime, everybody
wants a little piece of Roxie Hart.
This jar of cold cream set
her husband back 20 dollars!
Maybe this pretty little lady would
get some of that famous Roxie style.
It seems everybody these days
is rooting for Roxie Hart.
Take those flowers to the orphanage,
make sure they know who sent them.
So, kiddo, given any thought to what
you wanna do after Billy get you off?
Yeah, I think I'd like to go on stage.
I figured as much.
I already called the Morris office.
Really? How much is that gonna cost?
A fairly deal,
ten percent of all your takings.
Yeah, we'll see, Mama. Besides,
I don't even have an act yet.
Killing Fred Casely was your act. It 's
all the stiffs in the audience want...
...to say they saw somebody famous.
That 's a freak act.
And besides,
I am better than that.
Of course you are, cupcake. I mean,
you could be as big as Sophie Tucker.
You really think so?
Bigger than Cantor and Jolson.
You know, I always wanted to
have my name in all the papers.
Before I met Amos, I used to date
this well-to-do ugly bootlegger.
He used to take me out and show
me off. Ugly guys like to do that.
Once it said in the paper, "Gangland's
Al Capelli seen at Chez Vito...
with cute blonde chorine."
That was me.
I clipped and I saved it.
You know, all my life I
wanted to have my own act.
But no, no, no, always no.
They always turned me down.
One big world full of no.
And then Amos came along.
Safe, sweet Amos.
Who never says no.
I've never done this before.
But it 's such a special night and
you are such a great audience!
And I just, I really feel like I
can talk to you, you know.
Forget what you've read in the papers
and what you've heard on the radio!
Because, because... because
I'm gonna tell you the truth.
Not that the truth
really matters.
But I'm gonna tell
you anyway.
On the bed department,
Amos was... zero.
I mean, when he made
love to me, it was like...
it was like he was fixing
a carburetor or something.
I love you, honey.
I love you.
Anyway, I started
fooling around.
And then I started
screwing around.
Which is fooling around
without dinner.
Then I met Fred Casely, who said
that he could get me into vaudeville.
But that didn't quite work
out like I planned.
I guess it didn't really work
out too great for Fred either.
So I gave up on the whole
vaudeville idea.
Because you got to figure
after all those years...
opportunities just
passed you by.
But it ain't
No, no, no, well, it ain't
And now? Well, if this
Flynn guy gets me off...
and with all this publicity...
I got me a world full of yes!
The name on everybody's
lips is gonna be Roxie
The lady raking in the
chips is gonna be Roxie
I'm gonna be a celebrity
That means, somebody
everyone knows
They're gonna recognize
my eyes, my hair
my teeth, my boobs, my nose
From just some dumb mechanic's
wife I'm gonna be Roxie
Who says that murder's
not an art?
And who in case
she doesn't hang
can say she started
with a bang?
Roxie Hart