Hey, you Billy Costigan?
Yeah, who wants to know?
Well, nothing. I know
a Sean Costigan down on L Street.
Yeah, that's my cousin.
Connected. Not too bright.
Yeah, I know.
I mean, no offense.
Billy?
Yeah, it's me.
Oh, my God. Good to see you.
Aunt Kathy, how are you?
Oh, good to see you. Come on in.
They said you was in the staties.
I couldn't believe it.
I got kicked out,
like, four months ago.
Yeah, it was in the papers.
So you know.
And why are we graced
with your presence?
I brought your mother
some pictures of my father.
Look at the smile.
My mother had them. My
My mother's dead.
I'm sorry.
Sorry for your troubles.
I was at a funeral myself, man.
Myles Kennefick.
Knew him in school.
He was a young guy, you know?
It's terrible. It's a shame.
You remember that. What a night.
Listen.
I got, like
thirty thousand bucks, right? Insurance money.
Yeah.
You know, after my mother passed
and everything.
In your line of work, if I gave you
like, what, say, ten thousand,
what could I get back?
You know what you
You know what you usually say
at these moments.
What? What?
Come on, man.
Oh, come on, you fucking moron.
Come on.
What, you want me to say it?
I'm not a cop, all right?
I'm your fucking cousin.
You're bad.
You corrupt fuck, man.
You must be my cousin.
Fucking Ricans think
they know everything.
If they knew shit,
they wouldn't be Puerto Ricans.
R is for Ricans
P is for pigs
Would you shut the fuck up
for five seconds, huh?
That's right. You used to be a cop.
When we're working together
just limit it to two eight-balls an hour.
We're not even supposed to be doing
this shit this close to Worcester.
This side of Worcester.
Says who?
Says him. Says Costello.
God says, as far as you're
concerned.
No, no, he's no cop. He got out
of the joint three weeks ago.
Cunt cop.
No, no, no.
He talks like his shit don't stink,
but he's good people.
Well, I knew his father.
I liked his Uncle Jackie better.
Jackie was all right.
Uncle Jackie was excellent.
Fucking guineas.
To Jackie.
Uncle Jackie.
Cranberry juice.
It's a natural diuretic.
My girlfriend drinks it
when she's got her period.
What, do you got your period?
Fucking
Get off
Get your fucking hands off me!
Hey. Hey, hey.
Do you know me?
No. No.
Well, I'm the guy that tells you
there are guys you can hit
and there's guys you can't.
Now, that's not quite a guy
you can't hit
but it's almost a guy you can't hit.
So I'm gonna make a fucking ruling
on this right now
You don't fucking hit him.
You understand?
Yeah, excellent. Fine. Fine, fine.
I fucking know you.
I know your family.
You make one more drug deal
with that idiot fucking cop-magnet
of a cousin of yours
and I'll forget your grandmother was
so nice to me.
I'll cut your fucking nuts off.
You understand that?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
What are you drinking?
A cranberry juice.
What is it, your period?
Get him a cranberry juice.
Hey, fuckhead,
that's Jackie's nephew.
What? Oh, fucking what?
Get the fuck out of here.
Sorry I'm late.
Staff Sergeant Dignam is our liaison
to the undercover section.
His undercover work is extensive.
He's here to give us his report.
Sergeant Dignam.
Okay, my people are out there.
They're like fucking Indians.
You're not gonna see them.
You'll hear about them
through me or Captain Queenan.
You will not ever know the identity
of undercover people.
Unfortunately, this shithole has more
leaks than the Iraqi navy.
Fuck yourself.
I'm tired from fucking your wife.
How's your mother?
Tired from fucking my father.
Good. Today, girls
what I have is microprocessors.
Somebody, as you may already know,
stole twenty microprocessors
from the Mass Processor Company
out on Route one twenty eight.
These are the kind
they put into computers
that could put a cruise missile
up the ass of a camel
from a couple hundred miles away.
These pieces of plastic are worth
about a hundred grand a piece.
We got a guy working
for the company two months
walks out the door with
a box of processors on Tuesday
has a ticket for Florida
on Wednesday
but on Thursday, he gets found
in a Dumpster.
You know where that dirtball
started his life?
Southie projects.
What was his name, the departed?
Myles Kennefick.
Got the job with a forged UMass
transcript. UMass, Boston
which happens to
South Boston?
Oh, you're a fucking genius.
Who forged your transcript, dickhead?
His old man runs
the Hibernian Liquor Mart. Kennefick's.
We're not here to solve
the case of the missing scumbag.
We're here to nail Costello.
All right, look. We got a guy
says Costello's moving
the processors to China.
He set up the whole fucking job
and popped Kennefick.
You do not want to miss it
if Costello takes a dump.
We'd miss less if you made your
informants available to us and the FBI.
Without asking for too many details, do
you have anyone in with Costello now?
Maybe. Maybe not.
Maybe fuck yourself.
My theory on Feds
is they're like mushrooms.
Feed them shit
and keep them in the dark.
You girls have a good day.
Normally he's a very nice guy.
Don't judge him
from this meeting alone.
Now, Mrs. Kennefick,
I knew your son.
I knew Myles.
He was younger than me,
but he was behind me in school.
I wanna get these people
who did this to him.
Would you like to help us?
You wanna help catch the people
who forced your son to do a robbery
and then killed him?
Allegedly.
If he was killed,
he probably did something wrong.
But not the robbery.
That's not wrong.
He did something else wrong?
Wave to your girlfriend, honey.
I mean, fuck yourself.
Did you get that?
Allegedly or fuck yourself?
Welcome to the neighborhood.
Different breed down here, sarge.
I need a cup of coffee.
You making a house call?
Have I seen you professionally?
No, no. No, I know who you are, though.
I know.
Guys gotta use their service revolver
in the course of duty
and then they get to come to talk
to you about their feelings and whatnot.
No, no, I know how it goes.
You're a mental health professional.
I have an appointment on this floor.
Oh, well, you'll have fun. They're all
frigging crazy on that floor.
I'm one more up.
Oh, fancy policeman.
Yeah, that's right, fancy.
Are you a statie?
Yeah, I am. I'm actually
going to law school also.
Suffolk, nights?
Yeah, they don't run Harvard
at night, last time I checked.
When's the last time you checked?
Before I went to fucking Suffolk.
Okay, listen, I went to UMass.
I wasn't insulting you.
Well, I thought you were.
So now you gotta buy me dinner.
Maybe you can shoot someone
and then see me professionally.
I'll stab someone in the heart with an
ice pick if it gets me dinner with you.
That's all right. I'm a detective.
I'll find you.
No, sorry. I'm just joking.
I need the card. Card helps.
Nice to meet you, Madolyn.
Hi, Dad. I had no idea about the tail
until I saw it.
No, I couldn't.
I had the other guy with me, I couldn't
All right, it's a blue sedan
and then a white van.
It's fucked up with graffiti.
And the van is the audio surveillance.
All right, have a nice day.
Cut him here.
Bye bye.
Jerk ass!
Come on, Babu. I can't do anymore.
I cannot hold off.
Don't let me go back empty-handed.
Don't do this. I wanna help you.
Come to my store next Friday.
I'll give you the money.
This is Friday, Babu.
How many times I gotta tell you?
You keep on calling me Babu.
It's Singh, motherfucker.
I'm trying to help you.
You keep telling me I'm your friend.
You don't even know my fucking name.
I'm gonna catch a beating if I go back
again like last week.
See this guy? You see this guy? This
guy don't want you to have the money.
Because he wants to come back there
and squash your head.
I have one customer sitting here.
What I'm gonna do?
Business is bad? You opened a store
in an Irish neighborhood.
These are dirty people.
Don't you know that?
Sell potatoes,
I don't know what you're gonna do.
Excuse me, gentlemen. Sorry.
Know what I'm saying?
You fellas come from Providence?
It isn't any of your business,
is it, now?
What, are you fucking delivering
cannolis or something?
Hey! You are killing my business, man!
Fuck!
What's wrong with this fucking country?
Everybody hates everybody!
Get out of here. Get out of here!
Now, you also do probation work, right?
That's right, I see violent offenders.
Oh, bad guys.
Not necessarily.
Yeah, they got this but they don't got
duck l'orange.
Was your meal okay?
Yeah, no, the lobster was good.
I just, you know, because it was
a French restaurant I was surprised.
I'm waiting for you
to make your move.
Look, I don't know, if that thing moves,
I'm gonna shoot it.
I don't even know what it is.
So what's it like having people
find themselves. . .
in your office all day long?
Does it get messy with all those
feelings flying around?
Why, does that make you
uncomfortable?
No, no, no.
No?
No, I'm not on your couch.
Well, you know what Freud said
about the Irish?
Yeah, I do.
Yeah, if you actually do,
I'll see you again.
Who says I wanna see you again?
Don't you?
You should see your face.
Course I wanna see you again.
What Freud said about the Irish is
we're the only people who are
impervious to psychoanalysis.
Yeah, he said that.
I know he did.
So you're up shit's creek with
a client Iist full of mick cops.
I mean, opening up? Good luck to you.
Why do you do it, then?
Some people do get better.
Fair enough.
Sometimes I want people to forget
their personal bullshit and do their jobs.
Including the criminals?
If they don't do their jobs,
you don't have one.
I'll always have a job.
I'll just arrest innocent people.
Wait. You are trouble.
You don't know the half of it.
I'll arrest you right now.
My word against yours.
then I see her dancing at the wedding
with you know who.
I say, Why not go to
Parents Without Partners?
He goes, Ma, they're all losers
at the Parents Without Partners, so
So I say to him,
Princess Carolina of Monaco
Schuyler.
Do you know who I am?
No.
You met my friend Mr. French
the other night.
His real name Mr. French?
No.
Come with me.
I'm not the cops. I'm not asking you.
You know something, they just do not
stop having the Mafia in Providence.
And this
can cause me a lot of problems.
Those guys you tuned up
they're connected down Providence.
What they're gonna do
is come back with some guys
and kill you.
Which, sure as you're born,
they will do.
Unless I stop them.
Do you want me to stop them?
Is this something
I can't do personally?
I'm gonna have my associate
search you.
No one's searching me.
Search me for what?
Contra fucking band.
Take your shoes off.
Shoes.
I knew your father.
Yeah? Do you know he's dead?
Oh, sorry. How'd he go?
Stand.
He didn't complain.
Yeah, that was his problem.
Who said he had a problem?
I just said he had a fucking problem.
There's a man could've been anything.
Are you trying to say
that he was nothing?
Fuck.
I'm saying he worked at the airport.
He's clean.
Arm.
Yeah, come on.
What arm? What fucking arm?
Show me your arm. Flip it.
Makes me curious to see you
in this neighborhood.
He's clean.
And if I can slander my own
environment
it makes me sad, this regression.
Plus, I don't know if it's beyond some
fucking cop prick like Queenan
to pull you out of the staties
and send you after me.
I just can't know.
I don't know what they do
in that particular department, anyway.
Are you still a cop?
No! No!
Swear on your mother's grave
you're still not a cop?
I am not a fucking cop!
Are you gonna stop doing coke deals
with your jerkoff fucking cousin?
Yes. Yes, yes.
All right, all right, all right.
You're okay. You'll be all right.
Get your hand taken care of.
I'm sorry, but it was necessary.
As for our problem with Providence
let's not cry over spilled guinness
Who let
this IRA motherfucker in my bar?
Just kidding. How's your mother?
She's on her way out.
We all are. Act accordingly.
Here it is, Your Highness, as ordered.
Get in the car.
I wanna show you something.
What's got you all hot and bothered?
Get in the car. You'll see.
Do you trust him?
Well, these days
who's reliable?
His Uncle Jackie was.
Yeah, but you can't trust a guy
acts like he's got nothing to lose.
I'm reliable.
Arnold, you're one in a million.
Ten. Ten million.
What about your wife, Arnold?
Well, I thought she was.
She wasn't.
Well, she got reliable.
Don't you people
ever shut the fuck up?
Another county heard from.
One too many. She got a big mouth.
Answer this for me, will you?
The principles of detection tell me these
two gentlemen came from Providence.
Lieutenant Risteen, Lynn PD. I'd
appreciate you outta my crime scene.
Yeah, actually, it's my crime scene,
but knock yourself out.
Thanks.
I saw a dead guy. I think I'm having
posttraumatic stress.
Can I meet you for lunch?
All right, see you then.
Who's the lead detective?
Good. He's a lox.
Get the cops to look at Jimmy Pappas
for the hit. He had nothing to do with it
and he'll say so.
Look in his car, you'll find the gun that
did it, registered, official. Providence.
In the trunk
or the glove compartment?
Hey, you wanna see some dead guys?
Hey, this will get Captain Ellerby
on the six o'clock news.
No wonder you get ahead.
Have a seat, Bill.
Do you know John Lennon?
Yeah, sure, he was the president
before Lincoln.
Lennon said
I'm an artist.
You give me a fucking tuba,
I'll get you something out of it.
I tell you, Mr. Costello
I'd like to squeeze
some fucking money out of it.
Smart-mouth.
Too bad.
If you'll indulge me
Now what?
Choir practice.
Choir practice
The point I'm making
with John Lennon is
a man could look at anything
and make something out of it.
For instance
I look at you and I think
What could I use you for?
Get rid of this.
French.
Put it downstairs. Here.
Go ahead, thank you.
Maybe we could work something out.
Good.
And send this to his wife.
It was nice the way
you asked the guy
which hand he jerked off with.
I hope this do not shake Rita up.
As I remember,
she ain't that sentimental.
That was quick.
You think he's dead already?
We have to do it by phone.
I won 't do it
if I have to wear a wire.
No wires. Understand?
You don't know what this is like.
Microprocessors.
Micro what?
We'll probably be at war
with the Chinese in twenty odd years
and Costello is selling them
military technology.
Microprocessors,
chips, computer parts.
Anybody says anything about
anything like that
you let us know.
So who did the two guys
from Providence?
Jimmy Pappas.
What happened to Jimmy Pappas?
Jimmy had a rough month.
Jimmy had a heart attack in jail
and then he got himself knifed
at Boston City Hospital.
I believe it's been in the papers.
You seem quite happy
with that result.
It's a fucking result.
Yeah, but cui bono? Who benefits?
Cui gives a shit?
It's got a frigging bow on it.
I think you are a cop, my son.
Where's your license?
What license?
I don't see none. There's no such thing
as a license, of course.
But you, you definitely need
to have fucking one.
If you're not being run by us,
you're being run by someone else.
That means you're bringing
undesirable elements
into Mr. Costello's area.
I was going for my fucking cigarettes!
Hey.
That's Jimmy Bags.
He was rea-- I don't know.
What the fuck you doing?
I'm in the hole,
I pay him two grand.
There's no profit,
Then make more money.
This is America.
You don't make money, you're
a douche bag. Now what you gonna do?
Make more money.
That's the spirit!
Oh, fuck.
Don't worry about it.
The guy don't need
any fucking teeth anyway.
It's a small surveillance subunit,
but it's mine.
I didn't take this job to fuck up
or let anyone else fuck up.
I handpicked this group.
You're my A team. Now, our prim
Hi, Captain.
This crazy fuck
knocked Jimmy Bags' teeth out.
So?
He was
He was reaching for his cigarettes.
You're gonna give me shit?
It wasn't for no reason, Frank.
He reached into his coat.
I don't know if he's a bookie
or what he's doing.
Well, you do know
what a bookie does, don't you?
Yeah. Yeah, he pays you.
Queenan's compartmentalizing
everything in SIU
which is the right thing.
I don't trust half the troopers
out there anymore.
Bottom line
we think we might have a problem.
We think Costello's got a rat
in the state police.
Really?
Yeah, really.
Do we have direct access
to Queenan's undercovers?
No, no, not presently.
But I'm working on that.
Here, Bill, this is for you.
From now on, call the bar,
ask for Mikey. Just Mikey.
You ask for Mikey
because there is no Mikey.
You wait. We'll call you.
You got that?
Yeah, I got that.
Sorry, I didn't hear you.
I got that.
Good.
Hi, Dad.
I got promoted. All right.
Excuse me for one second.
You know
if your father were alive
and saw you here sitting with me
let's say he'd have a word with me
about this.
In fact, he'd kill seven guys
just to cut my throat.
And he could do it
which is maybe something you
don't know about William Costigan Sr.
So he never? I mean, never?
No. No, no.
He kept his own counsel.
He never wanted money.
You can't do anything
with a man like that.
Your Uncle Jackie
he also would kill my entire fucking
family if he saw me here with you.
And I think about this.
So what the fuck
are we talking about here?
Did you ever think about
going back to school?
School?
With all due respect, Mr. Costello
school is out.
Maybe someday
you'll wake the fuck up.
Good day, Fathers.
Mr. Costello.
Good morning, Francis, good morning.
You recall our chat?
Little boys
sucking on their peckers,
et cetera and so forth
I am as God made me.
Was that your rationale?
May I remind you, in this archdiocese,
God don't run the bingo.
May I remind you
that pride comes before the fall.
How's Sister Mary Theresa doing?
We had a tasty relationship
before she took her vows.
Enjoy your clams, cocksuckers.
Pay them.
Get the old bombardier a drink
on the house.
What do you got for me?
Uniform got him for suspended license.
However, he's a subject of
an open investigation
More than one. He's one of Costello's.
We're getting a warrant.
Can't get an address off him.
He paged his lawyer but
the lawyer hasn't called back yet.
Who's the lawyer?
Didn't know the name. Just a number.
Beeper number.
And the guy didn't show up?
No.
And he beeped him?
Twice.
Give me your phone. Turn that off.
What?
Turn the fucking camera off.
Give it to me. He doesn't know
what the fucking lawyer looks like.
Whose briefcase is this? All right.
It's off?
You're good.
Afternoon, Mr. Fitzgibbons.
He can't do that.
He just did.
You my attorney?
What do you think?
Have you made statements
or phone calls
I need to be made aware of?
I beeped you.
The card they gave me. That's it.
That's it?
That's it.
You need to call your mother
tell her you're not gonna be home
for supper.
Camera's off.
It's off. Call your mother.
Lookit, they're suiting up for a raid
right now.
I don't know where they're going,
but they do. And so do you.
So make the call.
Lookit, fuckstick,
you don't gotta trust me
just listen
to what I'm saying to you.
Mom, I'm not gonna make it home
for supper.
Sorry, yeah, I got held up.
Yeah, no, you carry on without me.
I'll talk to you later. Okay.
Bye.
Everybody out. Move.