Get in.
Hurry.
They're following us.
Who's-
Who's following us?
The drop has been
compromised.
Get down!
Stay down.
Here, take this.
I ain't shooting anybody.
Take the goddamn gun!
No!
Son of a
You stay back.
Don't move.
John?
Hi.
Where were you?
Sol-
Yeah, I talked to Sol.
He said you left
the office hours ago.
Why didn't you
call me?
Are you all right?
Honey?
John...
Please, talk to me.
Tell me what happened.
John,
open the door.
Come on, open the door!
Let me in!
Talk to me!
John!
Open the door!
Watch for cars, kids.
John.
William.
This is not what
I signed on for.
Every time
a car backfires
or a door slams-
I understand-
better than you
could possibly imagine.
You need
to calm down, John.
Now listen to me.
We're closing in
on the bomb,
in large part
due to your work.
Now don't you think your fear
is a small price to pay?
William, my circumstance
has changed.
Alicia's pregnant.
I told you attachments
were dangerous.
You chose to marry
the girl.
I did nothing
to prevent it.
The best way to ensure
everybody's safety...
is for you to continue
your work.
Well, I'll just quit.
You won't.
Why would I not?
Because I keep the Russians
from knowing you work for us.
You quit
working for me,
I quit working for you.
Parcher!
John, you all right?
John?
Turn it off!
Turn off the light!
Why would you
do that?
turn the light on?
What is wrong
with you?
You have to go
to your sister's.
I left the car out the back.
You take Commonwealth.
No side streets,
you stay where it's crowded.
John, I'm not going anywhere!
When you get to your sister's,
you wait for me to call you.
No, I'm not going.
Just get your things.
I'm not leaving-
Stop! Stop it!
Please, Alicia.
I'll explain
when I can.
Uncle John!
Hey, baby girl!
Wow, someone
needed a hug!
I saw you on the slate
and I thought to myself,
"How can I miss seeing
a guest lecture...
by the inimitable
John Nash?"
What's wrong?
I got myself into something.
I think I might need some help.
Well, now you tell me,
what is it?
Professor Nash!
Welcome!
After?
So, we see that
the- the zeroes,
of the Reimann
Zeta function,
correspond
to singularities...
in space-time,
singularities
in space-time-
and conventional
number theory...
It breaks down in the face
of relativistic exploration.
Sometimes
our expectations...
are betrayed
by the numbers.
Variables are impossible
to assign any...
rational value.
Professor Nash!
Hold it!
Professor Nash?
Professor Nash,
let's avoid a scene, shall we?
What do you want?
My name is Rosen,
Dr. Rosen.
I'm a psychiatrist.
Forgive me
if I don't seem
persuaded.
I'd like you
to come with me, John.
Just for a chat.
It appears I have
no choice.
Oh oh!
Help me!
Somebody!
Get off me!
I know who you are!
No, no, no,
no, don't.
Charles, they're Russians!
Call somebody!
Call somebody, Charles!
They're Russians!
Steady the leg.
Get away from me.
Stay away from me!
There, now.
All better.
Everything's
all right here.
Watch your head.
John?
Can you hear me?
Go easy now.
Thorazine takes
a little while
to wear off.
Sorry about
the restraints.
You've got one hell
of a right hook.
Where am l?
Ahem.
MacArthur
Psychiatric Hospital.
I find that
highly unlikely.
You made
a mistake.
My work is non-military
in application.
Which work
is that, John?
I don't know
anything.
There's no good
in keeping secrets, you know.
Charles?
I didn't mean to get you
involved in this.
I'm- I'm sorry.
Charles?
The prodigal roommate
revealed.
"Saw my name
on the lecture slate."
You lying son
of a bitch!
Who are you talking to?
Tell me who you see.
How do you say,
"Charles Herman" in Russian?
How do you say it
in Russian?
There's no one there, John.
There's no one there.
He's right there.
Stop!
I don't know anything!
l I don't know anything!
My name is John Nash.
I'm being held
against my will.
Somebody call
the Department of Defense.
My name is John Nash.
I'm being held
against my will!
What's wrong with him?
John has
schizophrenia.
People with this disorder
are often paranoid.
But
But his work.
He deals
with conspiracies.
Yes, yes, I know.
In John's world,
these behaviors
are accepted,
encouraged.
As such, his illness
may have gone untreated...
far longer
than is typical.
What do you mean?
How long?
Possibly since
graduate school?
At least that's when
his hallucinations
seem to have begun.
What are you
talking about?
What hallucinations?
One, so far,
that I am aware of.
An imaginary roommate
named Charles Herman.
Charles
isn't imaginary.
He and John
have been best friends
since Princeton.
Have you ever met Charles?
Has he ever come to dinner?
He's always in town
for so little time,
lecturing.
Was he at your wedding?
He had to teach.
Have you ever
seen a picture of him,
talked to him
on the telephone?
This is ridiculous.
I phoned Princeton.
According to their
housing records,
John lived alone.
Now, which is more likely-
that your husband,
a mathematician
with no military training,
is a government spy
fleeing the Russians-
You're making him
sound crazy.
or, that he has
lost his grip on reality?
Now the only way
I can help him
is to show him
the difference
between what's real
and what is in his mind.
Come on.
What's he been
working on?
His work
is classified.
He mentioned
a supervisor
by the name
of William Parcher.
Maybe Mister. Parcher
can clarify things
for us.
But I can't get to him
without clearances.
You want me to help you get...
the details
of my husband's work?
John thinks
I'm a Russian spy.
Is that what
you think?
What did
the doctor say?
Is he sick?
I don't know.
I want to see what John's
been working on.
You know you can't
go in his office.
It's classified, Alicia.
Stop. Oh!
Oh, my God.
Why didn't you
say something?
Alicia,
John's always been
a little weird.
He said he was
doing code-breaking,
that it was eyes-only.
Top secret, part
of the military effort.
Was he?
Well,
it was possible,
you know?
Directives come down
all the time
that some of us
aren't cleared for.
It was possible.
Possible, but
not likely.
Lately, he'd become
so much more agitated
and then
when you called
So, is this all
he's been doing
every day?
Cutting out
magazines?
Well, not all.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
I missed you.
I have to talk
to you.
Okay.
Alicia, I've been
thinking about it,
and I do realize
that my behavior...
and my inability to discuss
the situation with you...
must have appeared
insane.
I left you
with no other choice.
I do understand...
and I'm truly sorry.
That's okay.
Everything's
gonna be all right.
We just have to talk quietly.
They may be listening.
There may be microphones.
I'm gonna tell you
everything now.
It's breaking
with protocol
but you need
to know,
because you
have to help me
get out of here.
I've been doing
top secret work
for the government.
There's a threat
that exists
of catastrophic
proportions.
I think the Russians
feel my profile is too high.
That's why they simply
just don't do away with me.
They're keeping me here
to try to stop me...
from doing my work.
You have to get to Wheeler.
You have to find
William Parcher.
Stop.
He can help us.
Stop. Stop. Stop!
I went to Wheeler.
Good, good.
There is no
William Parcher.
Of course there is.
I've been working for him.
Doing what?
Breaking codes?
Dropping packages
in a secret mailbox
for the government
to pick up?
How could you
know that?
Sol followed you.
He thought it
was harmless.
Sol followed me?
They've never
been opened.
It isn't real.
There is
no conspiracy, John.
no William Parcher.
It's in your mind.
Do you
understand, baby?
You're sick.
You're sick, John.
John!
Code red.
Dr. Rosen, code red.
Observation room two.
John?
The implant has gone.
I can't find it.
It's gone.
You see, the nightmare
of schizophrenia...
is not knowing
what's true.
Imagine
if you had suddenly learned
that the people and the places
and the moments
most important to you
were not gone, not dead,
but worse
had never been.
What kind of hell
would that be?
Administering
insulin.
eight forty two AM.
How often?
Five times a week
for ten weeks.
John always spoke so fondly
of being here at Princeton.
And Hansen is running
the department now.
So he keeps reminding us,
and reminding us.
Yeah.
John won't come near
the campus, though.
I think he's ashamed.
Hey. Hey.
Want this?
So, Alicia, how-
how are you holding up?
Well, the delusions
have passed.
They're saying
with the medication...
and low stress
environment-
No, l I mean,
how are you?
I think often
what I feel
is obligation.
Or guilt
over wanting to leave.
Rage against John,
against God and-
But
then I look at him
and I force myself to see
the man that I married.
And he becomes that man.
He's transformed
into someone that I love.
And I'm transformed
into someone who loves him.
It's not all the time,
but
it's enough.
I think John is
a very lucky man
Alicia.
So unlucky.
This is us. This is it?
It's nice.
It's near where I work.
John? You've a visitor.
Hi.
I hope it's okay.
Hey ya, chief.
Cigarette?
Ah, no, thanks.
I quit, actually.
Hello.
Hey, John.
Have you met
Harvey?
Umm, l
John, there's no
Relax, it's okay.
There's no point
in being nuts if you can't
have a little fun.
Jesus Christ, John.
I should have known.
Here you go.
I can take those later.
You're supposed
to take them now.
Can I bring you something?
I'm okay.
Okay.
So, um yeah.
I- I was in town
giving a workshop.
I go back tonight.
You know, Bender,
he really wanted
to stop by
and you know, see you.
You know, say hi.
Squeamish?
Yeah.
I suppose
I would be, too.
But alas,
I'm stuck with me.
I'm trying to solve
the Reimann hypothesis.
Uh huh.
Oh, yeah?
I figured if
if I dazzle them,
they will have
to reinstate me.
But it's difficult
with the medication,
because it's hard to
see the solution.
You know, John,
you should go easy.
There are other
things besides
besides work.
What are they?
Shh
Shh.
What are you
thinking about?
What do people do?
It's life, John.
Activities available,
just add meaning.
You could try
leaving the house.
You know, maybe
talk to people.
You could try
taking out the garbage.
And there's some more
there's some more in
Who Who were
you talking to?
Garbage man.
Garbage men don't come
at night.
I guess around here
they do.
Sorry.