White and red wine
for your drinking pleasure!
Games.
One hundred and fifty days
of games.
He's cleverer than I thought.
Clever.
The whole of Rome
would be laughing at him
if they weren't so afraid
of his praetorian.
Fear and wonder
a powerful combination.
You really think the people
are going to be seduced by that?
I think he knows what Rome is.
Rome is the mob.
Conjure magic for them,
and they'll be distracted.
Take away their freedom,
and still they'll roar.
The beating heart of Rome
is not the marble of the senate.
It's the sand of the Colosseum.
He'll bring them death
and they will love him for it.
Spaniard.
Are you not entertained?
Is this not why you are here?
Spaniard! Spaniard!
What do you want?
Girl?
Boy?
You sent for me.
Yes, I did.
You're good, Spaniard,
but you're not that good.
You could be magnificent.
I'm required to kill, so I kill.
That is enough.
That's enough for the provinces,
but not for Rome.
The young emperor
has arranged
a series of spectacles
to commemorate his father
Marcus Aurelius.
I find that amusing
since it was Marcus Aurelius
the wise,
the all-knowing Marcus Aurelius
that closed us down.
So, finally, after five years
of scratching a living
in flea-infested villages
we're finally going back
to where we belong
the Colosseum.
Oh, you should see
the Colosseum, Spaniard.
Fifty thousand Romans
watching every movement
of your sword
willing you to make
that killer blow.
The silence before you strike
and the noise afterwards.
It rises.
It rises up like
like a storm
as if you were
the thunder god himself.
You were a gladiator?
Yes, I was.
You won your freedom?
A long time ago, the emperor
presented me with a rudis.
It's just a wooden sword.
The symbol of your freedom.
He touched me on the shoulder,
and I was free.
You knew Marcus Aurelius?
I did not say I knew him. I said
he touched me on the shoulder once.
You asked me what I want.
I, too, want to stand
in front of the emperor
as you did.
Then listen to me.
Learn from me.
I wasn't the best
because I killed quickly.
I was the best
because the crowd loved me.
Win the crowd
and you'll win your freedom.
I will win the crowd.
I will give them something
they've never seen before.
So, Spaniard,
we shall go to Rome together
and have bloody adventures
and the great whore
will suckle us
until we are fat and happy
and can suckle no more.
And then...
when enough men have died
perhaps you will have your freedom.
Here. Use this.
It's somewhere out there
my country
my home.
My wife is preparing food.
My daughters carry water
from the river.
Will I ever see them again?
I think no.
Do you believe you'll see them again
when you die?
I think so.
But then...
I will die soon.
They will not die for many years.
I'll have to wait.
But you would wait?
Of course.
You see...
my wife...
and my son
are already waiting for me.
You'll meet them again.
But not yet.
Not yet, unless
Not yet.
There.
There it is.
Out.
Go! Go! Out!
Good to see you again,
old friend.
Bring me fortune.
Have you ever seen anything
like that before?
I didn't know men
could build such things.
Win the crowd.
Get inside! Move!
Inside!
He sleeps so well
because he's loved.
Come, brother. It's late.
I will make Rome
the wonder of the ages.
That is what Gracchus and his friends
don't understand.
All my desires
are splitting my head to pieces.
Drink this tonic.
I think the time is almost right.
I could announce
the dissolution of the senate...
at the celebration
to honor our father.
Do you think I should?
Are the people ready?
I think you need your rest now.
Will you stay with me?
Still afraid of the dark,
brother?
Still.
Always.
Stay with me tonight.
You know I won't.
Then kiss me.
Sleep, brother.
Come on!
Take me.
All right, that's enough.
The emperor wants battles, and I don't
want to sacrifice my best fighters.
The crowd wants battles,
so the emperor gives them battles.
And you get the battle of Carthage.
The massacre of Carthage.
Why don't you go down to the prison,
round up all the beggars and thieves?
We've done that.
If you want to give away the best
gladiators in the whole of the empire
then I want double the rates.
You'll get your contract rates,
or you'll get your contract canceled.
You don't like it?
Then you can crawl back down
that shithole that you came from.
Cassius, please!
Cassius!
Gladiator, are you the one
they call the Spaniard?
Yes.
They said you were a giant.
They said you could crush
a man's skull with one hand.
A man's? No.
A boy's.
They have good horses in Spain?
Some of the best.
This is Argento
and this is Scarto.
They were my horses.
They were taken from me.
I like you, Spaniard.
I shall cheer for you.
They let you watch the games?
My uncle says it makes me strong.
And what does your father say?
My father is dead.
Master Lucius, it is time.
I have to go.
Your name is Lucius?
Lucius Verus, after my father.
Lower!
Claudius!
Yes?
More shields!
When the emperor enters
raise your weapons, salute him
and then speak together.
Face the emperor
and don't turn your back on him.
Go, and die with honor.
Hail, mighty Caesar!
Caesar! Caesar!
We who are about to die
salute you!
On this day
we reach back
to hallowed antiquity
to bring you a re-creation
of the second fall
of mighty Carthage!
On the barren plain of Zama
there stood the invincible armies
of the barbarian Hannibal.
Ferocious mercenaries
and warriors
from all brute nations
bent on merciless
destruction
conquest.
Your emperor
is pleased to give you
the barbarian horde!
Anyone here been in the army?
Yes.
I served with you at Vindobona.
You can help me.
Whatever comes out of these gates
we've got a better chance of survival
if we work together.
Do you understand?
If we stay together, we survive.
The emperor is pleased to bring you
the legionnaires
of Scipio Africanus!
To the death!
Kill! Kill! Kill!
Stay close!
Come together!
Staggered columns!
- Soon all your men will be slain.
- You don't have a chance.
Lock your shields!
Stay as one!
Hold!
As one!
Well done!
Hold!
Down low! Down low!
Yes!
Hagen!
This column to the chariot!
This column stay with me!
Quickly!
Get out there!
Hurry!
Maximus!
Single column!
We win!
My history's a little hazy,
Cassius
but shouldn't the barbarians
lose the battle of Carthage?
Yes, sire.
Forgive me, sire.
No, I rather enjoy surprises.
Who is he?
They call him the Spaniard, sire.
I think I'll meet him.
Yes, sire.
Hail to the barbarians!
Forward! Arms at ready!
Drop your weapons.
Gladiator,
the emperor has asked for you.
I am at the emperor's service.
Rise. Rise.
Your fame is well deserved,
Spaniard.
I don't think there's ever been
a gladiator to match you.
As for this young man, he insists you
are Hector reborn. Or was it Hercules?
Why doesn't the hero reveal himself
and tell us all your real name?
You do have a name?
My name is Gladiator.
How dare you show
your back to me?
Slave!
You will remove your helmet
and tell me your name.
My name is
Maximus Decimus Meridius
commander of
the armies of the north
general of the Felix Legions
loyal servant to the true emperor,
Marcus Aurelius
father to a murdered son
husband to a murdered wife
and I will have my vengeance,
in this life or the next.
Arms!
Live! Live! Live! Live!
Guards, at rest!
Maximus! Maximus!
Why is he still alive?
I don't know.
He shouldn't be alive.
It vexes me.
I'm terribly vexed.
I did what I had to do.
If Father had had his way,
the empire would have been torn apart.
You do see that?
What did you feel
when you saw him?
I felt nothing.
He wounded you deeply, didn't he?
No more than I wounded him.
They lied to me in Germania.
They told me he was dead.
If they lie to me,
they don't respect me.
If they don't respect me,
how can they ever love me?
Then you must
let the legions know
their treachery
will not go unpunished.
Poor sister.
I wouldn't want to be your enemy.
What will you do?
This way.